Guide to the Stanford Songs and Songbooks collection SC1319
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Songs and Songbooks collection
1892-1956
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
SC1319
5 Linear Feet
Arrangement
Series 1: Bound and unbound songbooks, 1893-1956; Series 2: Individual songs, 1892-1930; and Series 3: Class yells, 1892-1950.
Scope and Contents
Bound and unbound songbooks titles include A DECENNIAL OF STANFORD SONG 1895-1905, STANFORD SONGS, A COLLECTION OF CARDINAL FAVORITES, STANFORD FOOTBALL SONGS, LAGUNITA SONGBOOK, and CALIFORNIA UNIVERSITY SONGS. Individual songs include both printed songs and manuscripts.
Songs: Music & Lyrics
- Bound and Unbound Songbooks, Series 1
  - A Decennial of Stanford Song, 1895-1905 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A Decennial of Stanford Song, 1895-1905 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A Decennial of Stanford Song, 1895-1905 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A Decennial of Stanford Song, 1895-1905 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A Decennial of Stanford Song, 1895-1905 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A Decennial of Stanford Song, 1895-1905 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Songs of All the Colleges, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Songs: A Collection of Cardinal Favorites, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Songs: A Collection of Cardinal Favorites, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Songs: A Collection of Cardinal Favorites, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Songs: A Collection of Cardinal Favorites, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Songs Yells: A Collection of Cardinal Favorites, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Songs: A Collection of Cardinal Favorites, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Songs: A Collection of Cardinal Favorites, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Songs: A Collection of Cardinal Favorites, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Songs, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Songs, 1895 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Songs, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - No Title, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1899 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Songs, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Songs, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Songs, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Songs, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Songs, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Songs, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Football Songs, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Songs, N. D. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Principal's Dinner, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Lagunita Song Book (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - California University Songs, California Teachers Association (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Centenial Fascimile Edition, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Songs, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Decennial of Stanford Song (loose pages) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - A Decennial of Stanford Song (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Stanford Songs, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Individual Songs, Series 2
  - Stanford University Schottische with Waltz Refrain - Souvenir Edition by V.V. Clark, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The University March by W.B. Wells, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 96 Junior Hop Mach by AG. Kaufman, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Moonlight on the campus by W.B. Wells, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Moonlight on the campus by W.B. Wells - Score for Orchestra, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Waltzes - Souvenir Edition, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Waltzes - Score for Orchestra, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Waltzes - Score for Mandolin Guitar by E.R.Flint, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Cardinal Forever - Souvenir Edition by E.R.Flint, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Cardinal Forever - Score for Flute, Mandolin Guitar by E.R.Flint, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Cardinal Forever - Score for Orchestra by E.R.Flint, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Encina Club March by E.R.Flint, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Encina Club March - Score for Flute Guitar by E.R.Flint, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Encina Club March - Score for Orchestra by E.R.Flint, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Stanford Forever(The Spirit of the West) - Score for the Orchestra by E.R.Flint, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Forever(The Spirit of the West) - Conductor's Score by E.R.Flint, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Stanford Forever(The Spirit of the West) - Scores by E.R.Flint, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Stanford Pipe and Bowl by Arch Perrin, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - One, Two, Three, Four - Score for Orchestra, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sons of the Stanford Red - Misc. Info. On Composer/Pruit Music/ Scores for Orchestra, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Sons of the Stanford Red - Misc. Scores by W. Achi, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Cardinal is Waving by W.G.Paul, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Football Song by Griff Williams, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Stanford Yell, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Girl I Left Behind, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hail, Stanford, Hail - Handwritten Score/Score for Orchestra/Printed Scores by A.W.Smith, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hail, Stanford, Hail - Articles on/Words to by A.W.Smith, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Basketball Game - Hail Stanford Hail/Basket Ball Sons, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - My Stanford Home, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Hymn to Stanford by J.E.Kimbert, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Smiths for Hoover by C.A. Smith, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Sons of Stanford by E.V. Hegborn, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Trojan Horse by E.R. Flint, circa 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Loyalty Hymn by W.D. Allen, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - America and Stanford Hymn (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Assorted Songs (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bum Bum Song - Score for Orchestra (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Come Join the Band by Mrs. R.Riley (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Football Song (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Hail Alma Mater by W.Wilson (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Here Come the Men of Stanford (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - March of the Ancients (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - A Retrospect (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Son of a Gambolier (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Songs in Manuscript (Hail, Stanford Hail; Tin Horns Tooted; Eleven Men with a Pigskin Bag; Stanford Girls are Bright) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - The Stanford Axe by E.R. Flint (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Stanford Fair (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Stanford Mandalay (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Stanford Red by C. Ager (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Stanford Red by C. Ager (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Stanford Spirit March by E.R.Flint (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Stanford University (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Stanford Wins (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Class Yells, Series 3 (Correspondence)
  - All Stanford's Class Yells, 1892-1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Class Yells, 1894-1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Songs Yells, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Yells Songs (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Songs Yells, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Songs Yells, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)